<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>R-Ladies Melbourne Inc.</title>
<link>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/blog_index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/blog_index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.8.25</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>R Dev Day in Melbourne!</title>
  <dc:creator>Dionne Argyropoulos</dc:creator>
  <link>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_11_21_rdev.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p><img src="https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/images/2025_11_21_RDev.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>

<div class="no-row-height column-margin column-container"><div class="">
<p>Pao Corrales, Felicia Bongiovanni, Harriet Mason, Heather Turner, Dianne Cook, Dionne Argyropoulos, Minh Nguyen</p>
</div></div><p>Last Friday, Dionne, Felicia, Harriet and Daidai from our committee had the chance to participate in R Dev Day organised by Dr Heather Turner, and what a fantastic experience it was! 🎉</p>
<p>We spent the day coding alongside fellow R enthusiasts, not only in person in Melbourne, but also joining forces with amazing participants in Brisbane, Perth, and even internationally. 🌏</p>
<p>It was inspiring to collaborate, share ideas, and contribute to the R community together. Events like this remind me how energising and supportive the open-source world can be.</p>
<p>It was especially exciting to see such a great turnout of R-Ladies+ from R-Ladies Melbourne Inc, R-Ladies Amsterdam and R-Ladies Global!</p>
<p>Already looking forward to the next one! 💜💻</p>
<p>💜 Dionne on behalf of R-Ladies Melbourne</p>
<p><a href="../blog_index.html">Back to our blog home page</a></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>Event</category>
  <category>R Package</category>
  <category>R Dev Day</category>
  <guid>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_11_21_rdev.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Meetup: 12 Nov 2025: R-Ladies at R Dev Days with Dr Heather Turner</title>
  <dc:creator>Dionne Argyropoulos</dc:creator>
  <link>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_11_12_event.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p><img src="https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/images/2025_11_12_Flyer.png" class="img-fluid"></p>

<div class="no-row-height column-margin column-container"><div class="">
<p>Sign up on the R-Ladies Melbourne <a href="https://www.meetup.com/rladies-melbourne/events/311618693/"><strong>meetup page</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Time: Wed, Nov 12, 2025</p>
<p>5:30 PM to 7:30 PM AEST</p>
<p>Location: Monash City Campus (750 Collins Street, Docklands) and Online (Zoom)</p>
</div></div><section id="about-the-event" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="about-the-event">About the Event</h2>
<p>Under Heather’s research software engineering fellowship “Sustainability and EDI (Equality, Diversity, and Inclusion) in the R Project”, she has led the organisation of nine “R Dev Day”s, where R users work collaboratively on contributions to base R and to infrastructure that supports such contribution. Around 150 people have participated in these events, with good representation from groups that have historically been underrepresented in the contributor community, including women and gender minorities.</p>
<p>In this talk, Heather will give some insight into the tasks that people have worked on at R Dev Days, highlighting some examples that R-Ladies have been involved in. It’s broader than you might think, including translation, dashboards, websites, the contributor guide, and CRAN utilities, as well as the code and documentation of base R. Heather will explain different ways to get involved, including joining the upcoming hybrid events at <a href="https://pretix.eu/r-contributors/r-dev-day-oz-25/">Monash University</a> and the <a href="https://pretix.eu/r-contributors/r-dev-day-nz-25/">University of Auckland</a>.</p>
<p>There’ll also be food, drinks, and plenty of time to network with fellow attendees!</p>
</section>
<section id="speaker-dr-heather-turner" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="speaker-dr-heather-turner">Speaker: Dr Heather Turner</h2>
<p>Heather is a Research Software Engineering Fellow in the Statistics Department at the University of Warwick. In her fellowship, she is working on initiatives to improve sustainability and equality, diversity and inclusion in the R project. Heather has previously worked as a statistician for Pfizer and as a freelance statistical programming consultant. She has been an R user since 2001 and has co-authored several CRAN packages, notably the statistical modelling packages gnm, BradleyTerry2 and PlackettLuce. Heather is on the board of the R Foundation and chairs the R Contribution Working Group. She is also a leader of the Forwards taskforce for underrepresented groups and a co-organizer of R-Ladies Remote.</p>
<p>We look forward to seeing you there!</p>
<p>💜 Dionne on behalf of R-Ladies Melbourne</p>
<p><a href="../blog_index.html">Back to our blog home page</a></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Event</category>
  <category>R Package</category>
  <category>R Dev Day</category>
  <guid>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_11_12_event.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Meetup: 16 Oct 2025: R-Ladies &amp; SSA Melbourne Social Night: Happy 9th Birthday R-Ladies</title>
  <dc:creator>Dionne Argyropoulos</dc:creator>
  <link>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_10_16_event_social.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<section id="happy-9th-birthday-r-ladies-melbourne" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="happy-9th-birthday-r-ladies-melbourne">Happy 9th Birthday R-Ladies Melbourne 🎉</h2>
<p>Come unwind and connect with like-minded people at a joint event with R-Ladies Melbourne and the Statistical Society of Australia!</p>

<div class="no-row-height column-margin column-container"><div class="">
<p>Sign up on the R-Ladies Melbourne <a href="https://www.meetup.com/rladies-melbourne/events/311337114"><strong>meetup page</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Time: Thu, Oct 10, 2025</p>
<p>5:30 PM to 7:30 PM AEST</p>
<p>Location: Father’s Office (249 Lt Lonsdale St, Melbourne)</p>
</div></div><p>Whether you’ve been to one of our events in the past or you’re just starting out, this evening will be about building community and getting to know each other better.</p>
<p>Meet us at Father’s Office on Thursday 16th October for a casual meet up with good vibes and great company. Make sure to come on time to take advantage of the Father’s Office happy hour!</p>
<p>We look forward to seeing you there.</p>
<p>*Please note that food and drinks are not provided at this event and are at the attendee’s expense.</p>
<p>💜 Dionne on behalf of R-Ladies Melbourne</p>
<p><a href="../blog_index.html">Back to our blog home page</a></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Event</category>
  <category>Social</category>
  <guid>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_10_16_event_social.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Meetup: 18 Sept 2025: Plot Twist: Bringing Your ggplot2 Visuals to Life with ggplotly</title>
  <dc:creator>Dionne Argyropoulos</dc:creator>
  <link>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_09_18_event.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p><img src="https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/images/2025_09_18_Flyer.png" class="img-fluid"></p>

<div class="no-row-height column-margin column-container"><div class="">
<p>Sign up on the R-Ladies Melbourne <a href="https://www.meetup.com/rladies-melbourne/events/310808326/"><strong>meetup page</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Time: Thu, Sept 18, 2025</p>
<p>5:30 PM to 7:30 PM AEST</p>
<p>Location: DiUS (3/31 Queen Street, Melbourne) and Online (Zoom)</p>
</div></div><section id="about-the-event" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="about-the-event">About the Event</h2>
<p>Transform your static R plots into interactive, engaging visual stories! In this hands-on workshop, we’ll take pre-organised ggplot2 code and show you how to enhance it with ggplotly, making your data come alive for presentations, dashboards, and reports.</p>
<p>Through practical case studies, you’ll explore a variety of visualisations, learn why certain methods are best for different data types, and see how interactive features can add depth and clarity to your insights.</p>
<p>Whether you prefer to follow along in R with the required packages installed or explore the concepts via Google Colab and copy the code once you get home, you’ll gain actionable tips to elevate your R visualisations—no matter your platform. By the end, you’ll be ready to make your data clickable, hoverable, and truly dynamic.</p>
<p>There’ll also be food, drinks, and plenty of time to network with fellow attendees!</p>
</section>
<section id="speaker-dr-kirsty-mccann" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="speaker-dr-kirsty-mccann">Speaker: Dr Kirsty McCann</h2>
<p>Dr Kirsty McCann is an Associate Research Fellow working in malaria genomic epidemiology at Deakin University in Geelong. As a bioinformatician, Kirsty enjoys combining R coding, problem-solving, and infectious disease data analysis to answer a range of different research questions.</p>
<p>We look forward to seeing you there!</p>
<p>💜 Dionne on behalf of R-Ladies Melbourne</p>
<p><a href="../blog_index.html">Back to our blog home page</a></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Event</category>
  <category>ggplotly</category>
  <category>R Package</category>
  <guid>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_09_18_event.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Meetup: 14 Aug 2025: R-Ladies Social Night</title>
  <dc:creator>Felicia Bongiovanni</dc:creator>
  <link>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_08_14_event_social.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<section id="introducing-our-social-nights" class="level2 page-columns page-full">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introducing-our-social-nights">Introducing our Social Nights!</h2>
<p>Come unwind and connect with like-minded people at our first R-Ladies Social Night! Whether you’ve been to one of our events in the past or you’re just starting out, this evening will be about building community and getting to know each other better.</p>

<div class="no-row-height column-margin column-container"><div class="">
<p>Sign up on the R-Ladies Melbourne <a href="https://www.meetup.com/rladies-melbourne/events/310287919/"><strong>meetup page</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Time: Thu, Aug 14, 2025</p>
<p>5:30 PM to 7:30 PM AEST</p>
<p>Location: Father’s Office (249 Lt Lonsdale St, Melbourne)</p>
</div></div><p>Meet us at Father’s Office on August 14 for a casual meet up with good vibes and great company. Make sure to come on time to take advantage of the Father’s Office happy hour!</p>
<p>We look forward to seeing you there.</p>
<p>*Please note that food and drinks are not provided at this event and are at the attendee’s expense.</p>
<p>💜 Felicia on behalf of R-Ladies Melbourne</p>
<p><a href="../blog_index.html">Back to our blog home page</a></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Event</category>
  <category>Social</category>
  <guid>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_08_14_event_social.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Meetup: 09 Jul 2025: Using Git for Version Control and Collaboration</title>
  <dc:creator>Dionne Argyropoulos</dc:creator>
  <link>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_07_09_event.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p><img src="https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/images/2025_07_09_Flyer.png" class="img-fluid"></p>

<div class="no-row-height column-margin column-container"><div class="">
<p>Sign up on the R-Ladies Melbourne <a href="https://www.meetup.com/rladies-melbourne/events/308624008/?utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=share-btn_savedevents_share_modal&amp;utm_source=link&amp;utm_version=v2"><strong>meetup page</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Time: Wed, July 09, 2025</p>
<p>5:30 PM to 7:30 PM AEST</p>
<p>Location: DiUS (3/31 Queen Street, Melbourne) and Online (Zoom)</p>
</div></div><section id="about-the-event" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="about-the-event">About the Event</h2>
<p>Do you have trouble keeping track of changes in your code? Have you ever had to collaborate on a project with others and had to send files back and forth tediously? Git will be your best friend to solve these problems and many more!</p>
<p>This presentation will give you an introduction to Git, the basics of how to use it, and some of its very helpful applications such as collaboration and code reproducibility. The focus will be on the use of Git in conjunction with Github (yes, these are two separate things!). This will help you to effectively use one of the most powerful tools available to you and give you more confidence to code freely without fear.</p>
<p>There’ll also be food, drinks, and plenty of time to network with fellow attendees!</p>
</section>
<section id="speaker-felicia-bongiovanni" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="speaker-felicia-bongiovanni">Speaker: Felicia Bongiovanni</h2>
<p>Felicia is a PhD candidate at The Walter and Eliza Hall Institute of Medical Research currently researching the immune response to several infectious diseases using mathematical modelling and code.</p>
<p>We look forward to seeing you there!</p>
<p>💜 Dionne on behalf of R-Ladies Melbourne</p>
<p><a href="../blog_index.html">Back to our blog home page</a></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Event</category>
  <category>Git</category>
  <category>Github</category>
  <guid>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_07_09_event.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Meetup: 28 May 2025: Creating simple websites with Quarto + GitHub Pages</title>
  <dc:creator>Kathleen Zeglinski</dc:creator>
  <link>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_05_28_event.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p><img src="https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/images/2025_08_25_Flyer.png" class="img-fluid"></p>

<div class="no-row-height column-margin column-container"><div class="">
<p>Sign up on the R-Ladies Melbourne <a href="https://www.meetup.com/rladies-melbourne/events/307776181/?utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=share-btn_savedevents_share_modal&amp;utm_source=link&amp;utm_version=v2"><strong>meetup page</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Time: Wed, May 28, 2024</p>
<p>5:30 PM to 7:30 PM AEST</p>
<p>Location: DiUS (3/31 Queen Street, Melbourne) and Online (Zoom)</p>
</div></div><section id="about-the-event" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="about-the-event">About the Event</h2>
<p>Want to build your own website in minutes? Join us to learn how to create a simple, stylish website using Quarto, and publish it for free with GitHub Pages! 🌐✨ Perfect for portfolios, blogs, or project pages — no experience needed. You could make something like the RLadies Melbourne website or WEHI’s intro to R coursebook!</p>
<p>📝 Workshop details: 📅 28th of May 🕒 5:30-6:00pm (in-person networking &amp; refreshments) 🕒 6:00pm-7:30pm (hybrid workshop) 📍 DiUS 3/31 Queen St, Melbourne VIC 3000 or Online (zoom link posted on the day)</p>
<p>🛠 Before the workshop: ✅ Install RStudio or R + Quarto CLI ✅ Create a GitHub account (if you don’t have one yet) ✅ Bring your laptop and curiosity — we’ll handle the rest!</p>
</section>
<section id="speakers-danyang-dai-kathleen-zeglinski" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="speakers-danyang-dai-kathleen-zeglinski">Speakers: Danyang Dai &amp; Kathleen Zeglinski</h2>
<p>Danyang Dai (Daidai) is a third-year PhD candidate at the Queensland Digital Health Centre (QDHeC) at The University of Queensland. Her research focuses on advancing population health outcomes in the post-COVID-19 era. With a strong academic background in Econometrics and Biostatistics, Daidai is also a passionate advocate for the R programming language. She has actively contributed to the academic and professional communities through her involvement with organizations such as R-Ladies Melbourne and by creating educational resources for R programming.</p>
<p>Kathleen is a postdoc at WEHI, focusing on antibody bioinformatics and long-read sequencing. She is particularly interested in developing software pipelines to empower biologists to analyse their own data. Kathleen is also a co-convenor of the WEHI R course and passionate about R education.</p>
<p>We look forward to seeing you there!</p>
<p>💜 Kathleen on behalf of R-Ladies Melbourne</p>
<p><a href="../blog_index.html">Back to our blog home page</a></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Event</category>
  <category>Quarto</category>
  <category>Workshop</category>
  <category>GitHub Pages</category>
  <guid>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_05_28_event.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Meetup: 06 May 2025: Cross-Chapter TidyTuesday</title>
  <dc:creator>Dionne Argyropoulos</dc:creator>
  <link>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_05_06_event.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p><img src="https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/images/2025_05_06_Flyer.png" class="img-fluid"></p>

<div class="no-row-height column-margin column-container"><div class="">
<p>Sign up on the R-Ladies Sydney <a href="https://www.meetup.com/rladies-sydney/events/307276480/?eventOrigin=your_events"><strong>meetup page</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Time: Tues, May 06, 2024</p>
<p>1:00 PM to 2:00 PM AEST</p>
<p>Location: Online (Zoom)</p>
</div></div><section id="about-the-event" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="about-the-event">About the Event</h2>
<p>R-Ladies Canberra, Melbourne and Sydney are thrilled to host our first ever cross-chapter TidyTuesday and we would love to have you come along!</p>
<p>TidyTuesday is a weekly event created by the Data Science Learning Community for folks to develop new skills in a low-stakes, welcoming environment. Each week, a new dataset is released for everyone to play and explore. There is no limit to what you can do! You can produce a nice-looking table, or a story-telling graphic, perhaps even an intuitive Shiny interface – the choice is yours!</p>
</section>
<section id="what-to-expect" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="what-to-expect">What to expect</h2>
<p>Join a follow-along group or work independently on the same dataset for about 30 mins then come together to celebrate each other’s creations!</p>
<p>Come join us for a fun session on coding with R and Rstudio! This event is online only. All you need is your laptop!</p>
<p>We look forward to seeing you there!</p>
<p>💜 Dionne on behalf of R-Ladies Melbourne</p>
<p><a href="../blog_index.html">Back to our blog home page</a></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Event</category>
  <category>TidyTuesday</category>
  <guid>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_05_06_event.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Meetup: 03 Apr 2025: PGEforge</title>
  <dc:creator>Dionne Argyropoulos</dc:creator>
  <link>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_03_27_event.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p><img src="https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/images/2025_04_03_Flyer.png" class="img-fluid"></p>

<div class="no-row-height column-margin column-container"><div class="">
<p>Sign up on our <a href="https://www.meetup.com/rladies-melbourne/events/306510844/?eventOrigin=group_past_events"><strong>meetup page</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Time: Thurs, April 03, 2024</p>
<p>6:00 PM to 7:00 PM AEST</p>
<p>Location: Online (Zoom)</p>
</div></div><section id="about-the-event" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="about-the-event">About the Event</h2>
<p>Major advances in sequencing technologies, bioinformatics pipelines, and data analysis tools have transformed our ability to study malaria transmission and parasite evolution, providing valuable insights into malaria epidemiology from parasite genomic data. However, translating this genomic data into actionable insights for national malaria control programs remains a challenge. Many existing tools lack standardized workflows, comprehensive documentation, or interoperability, making it difficult for researchers and decision-makers to extract meaningful information.</p>
<p>To address this, Shazia and her team developed PGEforge (https://mrc-ide.github.io/PGEforge), a centralized, open-access repository for malaria genomic data analysis including analysis workflows, software evaluations, and reproducible tutorials. The Plasmodium Genomic Epidemiology (PlasmoGenEpi) network convened 18 experts to assess existing analysis tools, define key use cases for genomic data, and establish objective criteria for software evaluation. This initiative identified 40 Plasmodium genomic analysis tools with 22 prioritized for evaluation, defined eight key use cases for genomic data, and developed user-friendly reproducible tutorials for ten tools using shared datasets—all now accessible via PGEforge. Open-access platforms like PGEforge can empower researchers to adopt standardized practices and can help bridge the gap between genomic data generation, downstream analysis, and the effective use of these tools for malaria molecular surveillance towards actionable information for control programs.</p>
<p>In this talk, Shazia will showcase the functionalities of PGEforge, including real-world applications of genomic data use cases and analysis workflows, our approach to reproducible tutorials, and how we built this community-driven resource at a hackathon event using Quarto!</p>
</section>
<section id="about-the-speaker" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="about-the-speaker">About the Speaker</h2>
<p>Dr Shazia Ruybal-Pesántez is a genomic epidemiologist specializing in pathogen genomic epidemiology and its applications in malaria surveillance. Her research integrates population genetics, bioinformatics, and epidemiology to design analytical and statistical methods that enhance our understanding of malaria transmission dynamics. She is particularly interested in leveraging genomic data to optimize malaria surveillance strategies in response to emerging challenges such as increased localized outbreaks, drug resistance, and climate change. Through her work she aims to bridge the gap between data generation, analysis and real-world impact. She is also an avid R user (she is a former R-Ladies Melbourne president!) and is passionate about open science, training and capacity-building, and the development of accessible digital tools. She is also a consultant and instructor for Applied Epi, where she teaches applied epidemiologists and public health professionals to apply epidemiological methods using R.</p>
<p>We look forward to seeing you there!</p>
<p>💜 Dionne on behalf of R-Ladies Melbourne</p>
<p><a href="../blog_index.html">Back to our blog home page</a></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Event</category>
  <category>Bioinformatics</category>
  <category>Pipeline</category>
  <category>Workflows</category>
  <guid>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_03_27_event.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Meetup: 26th Feb 2025: Inspiring the Next Generation: R-Ladies Melb at “It Takes A Spark” Conference</title>
  <dc:creator>Dionne Argyropoulos</dc:creator>
  <link>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_02_22_event_redu.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p><img src="https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/images/2025_02_26_Flyer.png" class="img-fluid"></p>

<div class="no-row-height column-margin column-container"><div class="">
<p>Sign up on our <a href="https://www.meetup.com/rladies-melbourne/events/306093929/?eventOrigin=group_upcoming_events"><strong>meetup page</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Time: Wed, February 26, 2025</p>
<p>5:30 PM to 6:30 PM AEDT</p>
<p>Location: Online (Zoom Link Provided on Meetup)</p>
</div></div><section id="welcome-to-our-first-event-for-2025" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="welcome-to-our-first-event-for-2025">Welcome to our first event for 2025!</h2>
<section id="about-the-event" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="about-the-event">About the Event:</h3>
<p>How do we spark curiosity in coding, data science, and epidemiology among high school students? For the last several years, R-Ladies Melbourne has been running an engaging and interactive 80-minute workshop at the It Takes A Spark STEM Education Conference, introducing students to R, data visualisation, the power of clear science communication and concepts in epidemiology.</p>
<p>In this talk, Dionne will share insights from our experience delivering this workshop—how we designed it, the challenges we navigated, and the impact we’ve seen. We’ll also discuss key lessons learned, how we’ve adapted our approach, and our vision for the future of inspiring young minds in STEM.</p>
<p>Whether you’re an educator, mentor, or simply passionate about making STEM more accessible, join us to explore how we can continue to empower the next generation of data scientists and communicators.</p>
<p>See you there, R-Ladies Melbourne 💜</p>
</section>
<section id="about-the-speaker" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="about-the-speaker">About the Speaker:</h3>
<p>Dionne is a molecular epidemiologist and population geneticist currently positioned at WEHI (Walter and Eliza Hall Institute). Dionne’s avid interest in genetics, evolution and coding led her to apply these approaches to studies of infectious diseases, such as Plasmodium falciparum malaria in her Masters of Science and PhD, to P. vivax malaria and various microbes in her current first post-doc position. The research topics of interest include drug or antimicrobial resistance, spatiotemporal trends, epidemiological statistics, statistical modelling and machine learning techniques, data wrangling and visualisation. Her work has involved international collaborations in West Africa, North America and Southeast Asia, as well as supervision and support of students, with various opportunities for knowledge exchange and capacity-building in coding and genetic epidemiology. Being an active member of the R-Ladies Melbourne community, and the current President, has led to the development of practical content (workshops and the website) and has motivated her to learn and develop new techniques.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Event</category>
  <category>Education</category>
  <category>R-Ladies Melbourne</category>
  <guid>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2025_02_22_event_redu.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Meetup: 05th Dec 2024: End of Year Networking</title>
  <dc:creator>Dionne Argyropoulos</dc:creator>
  <link>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2024_11_25_event_EOY.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p><img src="https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/images/2024_12_05_Flyer.png" class="img-fluid"></p>

<div class="no-row-height column-margin column-container"><div class="">
<p>Sign up on our <a href="https://www.meetup.com/rladies-melbourne/events/304646177/?eventOrigin=group_upcoming_events"><strong>meetup page</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Time: Thu, December 05, 2024</p>
<p>5:30 PM to 7:30 PM AEDT</p>
<p>Location: In Person, The Clyde (385 Cardigan St, Carlton)</p>
</div></div><p>Please join us on Thursday 05th December 2024 on the rooftop at The Clyde Hotel in Carlton from 5.30pm. This is a networking catch-up with some light refreshments and will only be in-person. Please register your attendance on Meetup by the 1st December for planning purposes.</p>
<p>We have five outstanding mentors that coming to share the different journeys that brought them to their current roles in areas ranging from public health, genomics, bioinformatics, programming and software engineering!</p>
<p>Read more about each of these mentors on our <a href="../outputs/eoy2024.html">dedicated page</a>! Here you can find a biography, questions to ask and fun facts about each mentor! You can also leave any questions on our page by signing into your GitHub account.</p>
<p>We look forward to seeing you there!</p>
<p>R Ladies Melbourne 💜</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>Event</category>
  <category>Networking</category>
  <guid>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2024_11_25_event_EOY.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Meetup: 20th Nov 2024: Leveraging the Power of Data in Sport</title>
  <dc:creator>Caitlin Bourke</dc:creator>
  <link>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2024_11_06_event.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p><img src="https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/images/2024_11_20_Flyer.png" class="img-fluid"></p>

<div class="no-row-height column-margin column-container"><div class="">
<p>Sign up on our <a href="https://www.meetup.com/rladies-melbourne/events/304124032/?eventOrigin=group_events_list"><strong>meetup page</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Time: Wed, November 20, 2024</p>
<p>5:30 PM to 7:30 PM AEDT</p>
<p>Location: In Person, DiUS (Level 3, 31 Queen St, Melbourne)</p>
</div></div><section id="about-the-event" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="about-the-event">About the Event</h2>
<p>R-Ladies Melbourne is very excited to announce our next meetup event. We will be welcoming two data analytics experts, Elisa Koch and Lauren Boothby, who both work at the Australian Football League and will be joining us to discuss Leveraging the Power of Data in Sport.</p>
<p>Elisa has worked as a Data &amp; Analytics leader in the US and Australia in industries spanning finance, FMCG, technology, and sport. Currently, she is the Head of Data and Analytics at the Australian Football League (AFL). She is passionate about leading businesses to be more data driven at all levels of the business. Elisa is a people-first leader passionate about building high-performing teams built on diverse thinking and the ability to bring our authentic selves to work. Elisa serves as an Advisory Board Member for the Institute of Analytic Professionals Australia and is on the board of Spectrum Migrant Resource Centre, a non-profit focused on enabling people with migrant and refugee backgrounds to feel at home in Australia.</p>
<p>Lauren is a Senior Data Analyst and joined the Data and Analytics team at the AFL in 2023 from North Melbourne where she spent over five years working in both the football department and strategy team as a data analyst. Previous to this, Lauren has experience working with the West Coast Fever Netball Team and the West Coast Eagles Football Club.</p>
<p>Please join us on Wednesday 20th November 2024 at Dius Offices Melbourne from 5.30pm. We will first have a casual networking catch-up with some light refreshments, and the presentation will start at 6pm. You will also be able to join this event online if you are not able to join us in person. Please register your attendance (both in-person and online) on Meetup by the 14th November for planning purposes.</p>
<p>We look forward to seeing you there!</p>
<p>💜 Caitlin on behalf of R-Ladies Melbourne</p>
<p><a href="../blog_index.html">Back to our blog home page</a></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Event</category>
  <category>Data Science</category>
  <category>AFL</category>
  <guid>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2024_11_06_event.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Welcome to Our Website 💜</title>
  <dc:creator>Dionne Argyropoulos</dc:creator>
  <link>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2024_11_06_welcome.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<div style="display: flex;">
<div>
<p><img src="https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/images/rladiesmelblogo.png" class="img-fluid" width="500"></p>
</div>
<div>
<p>This is the first entry on our R-Ladies Melbourne website!</p>
<p>The intention of this website is to hold a place for of our chapter’s events, links, code, tutorials and so on, with the hopes that this will be a portal for members to continue to grow their skills and learn from each other.</p>
<p>Let us know via our <a href="rladiesmelbourne@gmail.com"><strong>email</strong></a> or <a href="https://github.com/R-LadiesMelbourne"><strong>github repo</strong></a> if there are any features you’d like to see or recommend!</p>
<p>Dionne on behalf of R-Ladies Melbourne!</p>
<p><a href="../blog_index.html">Back to our blog home page</a></p>
</div>
</div>



 ]]></description>
  <category>Admin</category>
  <category>Code</category>
  <guid>https://R-LadiesMelbourne.github.io/r-ladiesmelbourne.github.io/posts/2024_11_06_welcome.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
